<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Mychala Walker</title>
    <link>/projects/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Mychala Walker</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The Consistency of Voting Habits among College Students</title>
      <link>/projects/voting-college-students/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/voting-college-students/</guid>
      <description>Title: The Consistency of Voting Habits among College Students 
 Date: 4-1-2020 
 Author(s): Mychala Walker 
 Abstract: For generations, it was suggested that college students do not vote, despite research suggesting that voting is habit forming and youth voting can determine the trend for future civic engagement. The purpose of this project is to determine if voter disenfranchisement is the cause of such a lack of civil engagement among college students.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>X-Culture</title>
      <link>/projects/x-culture/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/x-culture/</guid>
      <description>Title: X-Culture 
 Date: 4-23-2020 
 Author(s): Arianna Bonacina, Claudio Luis De Melo Pereira, Austin Roberts, Juan Sebastian Casas Orjuela, Mychala Walker 
 About X - Culture: X-Culture is an international business collaboration and consulting project. Thousands of students from around the world work in teams to solve challenges from real international businesses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Social Determinants of Incarceration and Recidivism</title>
      <link>/projects/incarceration-recidivsm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/incarceration-recidivsm/</guid>
      <description>Title: The Social Determinants of Incarceration and Recidivism
 Website: https://dspg-young-scholars-program.github.io/dspg20halifax/

 Date: 8-7-2020
 Author(s): Riya Berry, Ellen Graham, Finn Roberts, Mychala Walker 
 Abstract: Incarceration and recidivism are very prominent issues in the United States. The US incarcerates more people per capita than any other country in the world. The rates are disproportionate for the African American and Hispanic communities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Factors contributing to Health Care Inequities in Petersburg, VA</title>
      <link>/projects/pwc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/pwc/</guid>
      <description>Title: Factors contributing to Health Care Inequities in Petersburg, VA
 Date: 8-7-2020
 Author(s): Kyra Faison, Kyle Jacobs, Courtney Lawson, Jaida Robinson, Mousa Toure, Mychala Walker 
 Abstract: Petersburg, VA is a city 20 miles south of Richmond, VA that is stricken with poverty, crime, low health outcomes, food desert status, and other poor demographic features.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Demonstrating the Value of the Appomattox Trail</title>
      <link>/projects/folar/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/folar/</guid>
      <description>Title: Demonstrating the Value of the Appomattox Trail
 Date: 8-7-2020
 Author(s): Kyra Faison, Kyle Jacobs, Courtney Lawson, Jaida Robinson, Mousa Toure, Mychala Walker 
 Abstract: Friends of the Lower Appomattox River (FOLAR) partnered with the Virginia State University DSPG team to show the value of the Appomattox River through economic and social means.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>