<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mychala Walker</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Mychala Walker</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The Consistency of Voting Habits among College Students</title>
      <link>/projects/voting-college-students/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/voting-college-students/</guid>
      <description>Title: The Consistency of Voting Habits among College Students 
 Date: 4-1-2020 
 Author(s): Mychala Walker 
 Abstract: For generations, it was suggested that college students do not vote, despite research suggesting that voting is habit forming and youth voting can determine the trend for future civic engagement. The purpose of this project is to determine if voter disenfranchisement is the cause of such a lack of civil engagement among college students.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Social Determinants of Incarceration and Recidivism</title>
      <link>/projects/incarceration-recidivsm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/incarceration-recidivsm/</guid>
      <description>Title: The Social Determinants of Incarceration and Recidivism
 Website: https://dspg-young-scholars-program.github.io/dspg20halifax/

 Date: 8-7-2020
 Author(s): Riya Berry, Ellen Graham, Finn Roberts, Mychala Walker 
 Abstract: Incarceration and recidivism are very prominent issues in the United States. The US incarcerates more people per capita than any other country in the world. The rates are disproportionate for the African American and Hispanic communities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Factors contributing to Health Care Inequities in Petersburg, VA</title>
      <link>/projects/pwc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/pwc/</guid>
      <description>Title: Factors contributing to Health Care Inequities in Petersburg, VA
 Date: 8-7-2020
 Author(s): Kyra Faison, Kyle Jacobs, Courtney Lawson, Jaida Robinson, Mousa Toure, Mychala Walker 
 Abstract: Petersburg, VA is a city 20 miles south of Richmond, VA that is stricken with poverty, crime, low health outcomes, food desert status, and other poor demographic features.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Demonstrating the value of the Appomattox Trail</title>
      <link>/projects/folar/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/folar/</guid>
      <description>Title: Demonstrating the value of the Appomattox Trail
 Date: 8-7-2020
 Author(s): Kyra Faison, Kyle Jacobs, Courtney Lawson, Jaida Robinson, Mousa Toure, Mychala Walker 
 Abstract: Friends of the Lower Appomattox River (FOLAR) partnered with the Virginia State University DSPG team to show the value of the Appomattox River through economic and social means.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to my website!</title>
      <link>/blog/welcome-to-my-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/welcome-to-my-website/</guid>
      <description>Hello! Welcome to my website.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>AboutMychala Walker is a Virginia State University Presidential Scholar, Andrew Young Student Leader, and Thurgood Marshall College Fund scholar. During her time at Virginia State, she has studied Political Science and gained numerous accolades including Outstanding Freshman of the Year, Outstanding Sophomore of the Year, and the Rosa Parks Award for Academic Excellence. You can learn more of these accomplishments in the Resume tab.Mychala has worked on both solo and team research projects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/resume/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/resume/</guid>
      <description>EDUCATION  Virginia State University, 4.0/4.0 GPA Expected May 2022 Petersburg, VA Bachelor of Science in Political Science Minor in Business Management/ Public Administration Honors Program Student
 Relevant Coursework:  State and Local Government, US Government, Contemporary Political Thought, Comparative Government, Constitutional and Civil Liberties, International Business, Introduction to Git, Introduction to R, Analyzing US Census Data in R
 Leadership Experience:  Vice President of Rainbow Soul, 2019 Student Honors Council member, 2019 - 2020 Student Senate, Honors Program Representative, 2019 -2020  Activities &amp;amp; Honors:  Virginia State University, Presidential Scholar, 2018 – 2022 Virginia State University, Outstanding Freshman of the Year, 2019 Virginia State University Political Science Department, Rosa Parks Award for Academic Excellence, 2019 Andrew Young Student Leader, Andrew Young Emerging Leaders, 2019 National Society of Leadership and Success, Sigma Alpha Pi Thurgood Marshall College Fund, TMCF Scholar, 2019 Alpha Kappa Alpha Pi Rho Omega Chapter, HBCU for Life Scholarship Recipient, 2019 Virginia State University, Outstanding Sophomore ofthe Year, 2020 Virginia21, VA21 Student Leader, 2020 X-Culture, X-Culture Scholar, 2020 X-Culture, Best Team Award, 2020 Educational Testing Service, TMCF-ETS Scholarship Recipient, 2020 CULTURAL IMMERSION Traveled to Greece, Italy, and Spain in Summer of 2019 Engaged in local communities, increasing cultural acumen Practiced Spanish and Greek fluency by interacting with local businesses Developed cultural awareness through multiple tours Acquired insight into European and Peruvian beliefs and religions Gained knowledge in European countries and South American countries WORK &amp;amp; LEADERSHIP EXPERIENCE  January 2019 – February 2019, Office of State Senator Jeremy McPike, Richmond, VA  Intern An internship position where I worked in the Virginia General Assembly and was responsible conducting research, speaking with constituents, attending legislative meetings, and completing general office tasks - Replied electronically weekly to 35 citizens’ issues, questions, and concerns using Microsoft Word, Google Drive, and Gmail - Recorded all daily 5 inbound and outbound pieces of mail and 15 citizen visits to the office per week.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>